<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><soap:Envelope xmlns:soap="http://www.w3.org/2003/05/soap-envelope" xmlns:wsnt="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsn/b-2" xmlns:wsa="http://www.w3.org/2005/08/addressing">
  <soap:Header>Header</soap:Header>
  <soap:Body>
    <wsnt:Notify>
      <wsnt:NotificationMessage>
        <wsnt:Topic>ALERT.MLSensor.MailNew</wsnt:Topic>
        <wsnt:ProducerReference>
          <wsa:Address>http://www.alert-project.eu/MLSensor</wsa:Address>
        </wsnt:ProducerReference>
        <wsnt:Message>
          <ns1:event xmlns:ns1="http://www.alert-project.eu/" xmlns:o="http://www.alert-project.eu/ontoevents-mdservice" xmlns:r="http://www.alert-project.eu/rawevents-forum" xmlns:r1="http://www.alert-project.eu/rawevents-mailinglist" xmlns:r2="http://www.alert-project.eu/rawevents-wiki" xmlns:s="http://www.alert-project.eu/strevents-kesi" xmlns:sm="http://www.alert-project.eu/stardom" xmlns:s1="http://www.alert-project.eu/strevents-keui" xmlns:sc="http://www.alert-project.eu/socrates" xmlns:p="http://www.alert-project.eu/panteon" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.alert-project.eu/alert-root.xsd"  >
            <ns1:head>
              <ns1:sender>MLSensor</ns1:sender>
              <ns1:timestamp>1348472809957</ns1:timestamp>
              <ns1:sequencenumber>17</ns1:sequencenumber>
            </ns1:head>
            <ns1:payload>
              <ns1:meta>
                <ns1:startTime>1348472809957</ns1:startTime>
                <ns1:endTime>1348472809960</ns1:endTime>
                <ns1:eventName>ALERT.MLSensor.MailNew</ns1:eventName>
                <ns1:eventId>17</ns1:eventId>
                <ns1:eventType>Request</ns1:eventType>
              </ns1:meta>
              <ns1:eventData>
                <r1:message>
                  <r1:from><![CDATA[wstephenson at kde.org (Will Stephenson)]]></r1:from>
                  <r1:date>Fri, 06 Jan 2006 11:07:05 +0200</r1:date>
                  <r1:subject><![CDATA[[Kde-hardware-devel] networkstatus]]></r1:subject>
                  <r1:content><![CDATA[Le Jeudi 5 Janvier 2006 20:22, Eric Gaumer a ?crit :
> NetworkManager seems to be built around libglib2 and I'm not sure how I
> feel about that. It seems more geared toward GNOME APIs though I do realize
> it's completely neutral.

Yes, in particular since on our side it would be accessed via the exposed DBUS 
methods.

> In any event if you look at the backend of NetworkManager you'll see things
> such as:
>
>         /* Add default gateway */
>         buf = g_strdup_printf ("/sbin/ip route add default dev %s", iface);
>         nm_spawn_process (buf);
>         g_free (buf);
>
> So what I propose to do with libiproute2 fills a void that NetworkManager
> doesn't address at this time.
> [...]
> At any rate, I am but one person with limited time to offer so my immediate
> short term goal is to get a library built from iproute that could possibly
> be used in a number of applications.

Indeed. That's a good reason to have such a project around.

> I'm here on the KDE Hardware list because I've recently moved from Gnome to
> KDE and think that KDE4 is going to be a major breakthrough on the desktop.
> Being that I use KDE, I'm obviously interested in the direction it is
> heading. Though I would like to see my efforts being enjoyed in a
> homogeneous fashion, I would sleep better knowing it would benefit KDE and
> thus have direct benefits on myself.

Yes, it would benefit KDE. Solid is higher level, and tries to encapsulate the 
underlying platform. But we build upon this underlying platform, so if it's 
cleaner and more robust it'll make our work easier and we'll be able to 
concentrate more directly on desktop applications needs. The more we cover 
those needs the best future KDE applications will be. That's a "win-win" 
situation IMHO.

> I've read of a libkdehw but haven't seen any code. Is this anything of
> substance at the moment?

This one will surely number 1 on the wiki. :-)
Ok, it's currently in the KDE subversion repository : branches/work/kdehw
Please note that currently it only addresses hardware discovery, there's no 
code for network management yet.

> Is it meant to address the true core or is it an 
> API to provide an interface between KDE and some lower core? Possibly
> something along the lines of libiproute2?

It's an API to provide an interface between KDE and lower level facilities. So 
possibly will be able to have a backend using libiproute2 directly, but it's 
more likely that we'll communicate with a daemon over DBUS

> I only ask because if it's a true core than I would switch my focus to
> helping that evolve. I have to imagine that something built from iproute2
> code is probably as low level as you'll see in user space. Building the
> library from iproute is more of a reorganization of code. All that code is
> written and maintained so my goal is to restructure the build process so
> that the 'ip' frontend gets separated from the actual functions which would
> be used to build a core library that 'ip' would merely link against.
>
> This way those developers who already maintain iproute2 could continue to
> maintain that project and I could shift to something at a higher level like
> the Solid framework.

Well, that really depends on your tastes. ;-)
But yes, Solid is higher level than your current work.

> So it would seem that a library built from iproute would in fact be helpful
> because one consideration has been the use of NetworkManager which would
> obviously benefit from my work.

There's no doubt about this IMHO, that library will be helpful. I doubt that 
we'll use it directly from Solid though. From what I know about 
NetworkManager that would be a good move if it uses it.

> Wether NetworkManager morphs into something larger or something similar but
> larger comes along, it seems the Solid framework would ultimately benefit.

Yes. Through the relevant backends.

> As of now I simply build a standalone library but as I stated earlier, I
> would rather restructure things inside of iproute so that it contains the
> core library. I'm not too sure how those developers would feel about that
> but I don't think it would disrupt them too much.

Did you contact them about your plans? If not it would be wise to do it I 
guess.

> The library I speak of has a very direct goal; to provide an interface to
> the functions that iproute2 offers. Anything outside of that would be
> addressed in a lateral component and/or a higher level one.

Which definitely means that your library alone wouldn't be enough for our 
needs. On the other hand, having a daemon like NetworkManager using it is an 
idea that pleases me.

I'm glad to know someone is trying to address this library need, in the end 
it'll result in cleaner code for some tools (NetworkManager looking like a 
natural client for such a work).

Regards.
-- 
K?vin 'ervin' Ottens, http://ervin.ipsquad.net
"Ni le ma?tre sans disciple, Ni le disciple sans ma?tre,
Ne font reculer l'ignorance."
]]></r1:content>
                </r1:message>
              </ns1:eventData>
            </ns1:payload>
          </ns1:event>
        </wsnt:Message>
      </wsnt:NotificationMessage>
    </wsnt:Notify>
  </soap:Body>
</soap:Envelope>